welcome back to another darktable
欢迎回到另一张暗桌
tutorial in our last tutorial we learned
教程在上一个教程中 我们学到了
about masking using drawn masks so we
关于使用绘制的面具进行蒙版 所以我们
drew a mask and we change the size of it
画了一个面具 我们改变了它的大小
and the feather and we had applied
和羽毛 我们申请了
changes our module would only happen
我们的模块只会发生更改
within that mask well in this video
在这个视频中很好地展示了这个面具
we're going to be looking at parametric
我们将看到的是参数
masks which let us do something a little
让我们做点什么的面具
bit different
略有不同
it lets us choose based on the pixels we
它让我们根据我们选择的像素进行选择
can choose based on color based on the
可以根据颜色进行选择
brightness of the pixel or based on some
像素的亮度或基于某些
other attributes of pixels as well so
像素的其他属性也是如此
it's really nice in this case we
在这种情况下 我们真的很好
wouldn't have to if we didn't have
如果我们没有的话就不用这么做了
parametric masking we'd have to grab our
参数掩码 我们必须抓住我们的
paths tool and we'd have to mask off
路径工具 我们将不得不遮罩
every individual thing if we wanted to
每一件事如果我们想的话
change the sky color for example we have
更改天空颜色 例如我们有
two masks here we have two masks here
这里有两个口罩我们这里有两个口罩
here this little part up here so it's
在这上面的这一小部分 所以它是
nice if we can just select all the sky
如果我们可以选择所有的天空 那就好了
based on a common attribute that it has
基于它所具有的共同属性
like its color or its brightness and
喜欢它的颜色或亮度
that's exactly what we can do with
这正是我们所能做的
parametric masking so oh I want to show
参数掩码所以哦我想展示
you one thing though I didn't talk about
你有一件事我没有谈到
last time I don't think if we draw a
上次我不认为如果我们抽签
mask and then we come over here and we
戴着面具 然后我们来到这里
try to apply that mask with on this
试着把面具贴在这个上面
color corrector for example we go to
例如颜色校正器 我们转到
drawn mask and we say use the circle one
画出面具 我们说用圆圈面具
we can see what this mask is doing by
我们可以看到这个面具在做什么
just making it we can make a change on
只要做到 我们就可以做出改变
the image and we can see how that change
我们可以看到这幅图是如何改变的
changes the way our image looks or we
改变我们形象的样子 或者我们
could also if we don't if our change is
如果我们不这样做 如果我们的变化是
very very subtle maybe let's say we're
非常非常微妙 也许可以说我们是
only altering the color a teeny tiny bit
只是稍微改变了一下颜色
and it's hard to tell what's exactly
很难说清楚到底是什么
happening in there we can look at our
在那里发生的我们可以看到我们的
masks in more detail by clicking this
通过单击此按钮 可以更详细地显示掩码
little white icon this little white
白色小图标 这个白色小图标
square with a circle in it if we click
如果我们点击 里面有一个圆圈的正方形
that it turns our whole image not
它使我们的整个形象不会
permanently it just for the help of met
永久地 它只是为了MET的帮助
of us masking it turns our image black
我们掩盖它会让我们的形象变得黑色
and white and it shows us our mask in
和白色 它向我们展示了我们的面具
yellow so then we can see if we hover
黄色 这样我们就可以看到我们是否在空中盘旋
over the feather and change the feather
越过羽毛 改变羽毛
we can kind of see more what that's
我们可以更多地了解这是什么
doing how that's fading out our mask and
如何让我们的面具褪色
so we can kind of see more how our mask
所以我们可以更多地看到我们的面具
is behaving relative to the image behind
是相对于背后的形象表现出来的
it this is gonna be a really important
如果这将是一个非常重要的
thing and really good to use in our
它非常适合用在我们的
parametric masking that's why I bring
参数掩蔽这就是我为什么
that up I don't know if I talked about
我不知道我有没有说过
last time either
上次也不是
masks will just click on it and then we
面具只需点击它 然后我们
can right-click on it and it'll go away
用鼠标右键点击它 它就会消失
so now we see our whole image is being
所以现在我们看到我们的整个形象是
masked because we don't have anything
戴着面具因为我们什么都没有
drawn and then when we draw something it
然后当我们画一些东西的时候
comes back in there anyway
不管怎样 都会回到那里
let's click this little icon right here
让我们点击这里的这个小图标
to reset all everything in here our
要重置我们这里的所有内容
blend is back to off and now we're going
Blend又回来了 现在我们要去
to click the drop down left click and go
要单击下拉菜单 请左键单击并开始
down to parametric mask that gives us
向下到参数遮罩 为我们提供
some more options
更多选项
oops I made a change just reset that
哦 我做了个改变 刚刚重置了
capacity so we still have this little
容量 所以我们仍有这一小部分
button here and I'm gonna click it this
这里的按钮 我要点击它
time so we click this and that's going
时间到了 我们点击这个 然后它就开始了
to make it so our whole image is masked
为了让我们的整个形象都被遮盖
out right now and so now we can adjust
现在就出去 所以现在我们可以调整
these channels I'm just gonna show you
我要向你们展示的这些频道
what it does if we keep it on this L
如果我们把它放在这个L身上会怎么样
it's the brightness Channel and as we
这是亮度频道 当我们
drag this around its we can see certain
把它拖来拖去 我们可以看到
parts of our image shine through and
我们的形象的一部分闪耀着
certain parts remain masked so in this
某些部分在这个过程中仍然被掩盖着
case it's the darker pixels that are
如果是较暗的像素
shining through or coming through and
穿透或穿透
it's the lighter pixels that are being
它是更亮的像素
masked so that's because we're on this L
蒙面所以那是因为我们在L
there's different channels we can do it
我们有不同的渠道可以做到
based off of hue so based off of a color
基于色调如此基于颜色
of the pixel L is based off of the
的像素 L是基于
brightness of the pixel there's some
像素的亮度有一些
other channels here we'll be looking at
我们将在这里关注其他频道
later but let's just adjust these
稍后 但让我们调整一下这些
triangles here this is sort of
这里是三角形 这是一种
brightness see we have dark pixels here
亮度看 我们这里有暗像素
light pixels here and everything in
这里的光线像素和里面的所有东西
between and so we can come in here and
所以我们可以到这里来
adjust to select just a certain part and
调整以仅选择某个部分 然后
if we're curious if we want to find we
如果我们好奇想不想找到我们
can use this little dropper here this
可以在这里使用这个小滴管
little color picker or this picker tool
小拾色器或此拾色器工具
and we can click and select an area and
我们可以点击并选择一个区域
that will draw a line so that's area I
这将画出一条线 所以这是第一个区域
selected right here let's do this one is
在这里选择 让我们来做这件事
showing right here as a white vertical
在这里显示为白色竖线
line on this bar
在这栏上划一条线
there's input and output so we're
有输入和输出 所以我们
selecting based on the input right now
现在根据输入进行选择
so we're going to want to be on this
所以我们会想要参与到这个项目中
one's gonna want to be on the right side
有人会想要站在正确的一边
of this little white vertical line and
在这条白色的垂直线上
this one's gonna be on the left side of
这一个将会在左边
that white vertical line and then we can
那条白色的垂直线 我们就可以
sort of fine-tune this to capture all
对此进行微调 以捕获所有
the light the spectrum of light pixels
光在光像素的光谱中
that are within the sky so I'm doing
在天空中 所以我在做
this top triangle now the top triangle
这个顶端三角形现在是顶端三角形
is sort of like our hard edge out of our
有点像我们的坚硬锋芒
shape that we were doing earlier and
形成我们之前做过的形状
this bottom trying
这底部的尝试
sort of like the soft feathered edge if
有点像柔软的羽毛边缘 如果
you can think of it that way is sort of
你可以这样想 这是一种
the fade around the pixels so we see
像素周围的褪色 所以我们可以看到
this looks very hard and sharp right now
现在看起来很硬很锋利
but as we adjust this bottom triangle it
但当我们调整这个底部的三角形时
becomes softer and more of like faded
变得更柔和 更像褪色
into the other pixels around it does
到它周围的其他像素中去
that make sense it's kinda hard to see
这就说得通了 很难看出
there anyway so the top white triangle
不管怎么说 上面的白色三角形
is hard the bottom one is soft so we'll
是硬的吗 下面的是软的 所以我们
put that right there
把它放在那里
and that looks pretty good so now we're
这看起来很好 所以现在我们
still in our what's this thing called if
还在我们这玩意儿叫什么来着
we hover over it tells us display mask
我们将鼠标悬停在它上面会告诉我们显示掩码
over color channel mode anyway we're
通过颜色通道模式 无论如何我们都是
still on this mode let's click this to
仍在此模式下 让我们点击此按钮
take that off and now any changes we
把它脱下来 现在我们有什么改变
apply this the one that we use this in
应用这个 我们在其中使用这个
is this color corrector so now the
这个颜色校正器现在是
changes that we apply are going to
我们应用的更改将
happen to our masked area and not to the
发生在我们的蒙版区域 而不是
leaves not to everything else that's not
不会留给其他一切不是的东西
masked so we can change the color of the
遮罩 以便我们可以更改
sky in this case without affecting the
在这种情况下 天空不会影响
leaves directly or vice versa maybe we
直接离开或反之亦然 也许我们
maybe the sky was fine if you want to
如果你想的话也许天空是好的
invert that we can do it just like we
反之 我们可以像我们这样做
did before this icons right here this
在这个图标之前 就在这里
little circle with the white and black
黑白相间的小圆圈
on it we click that and now our
在上面我们点击它 现在我们的
selection is inverted we can see what
选择颠倒了 我们可以看到
that looks like by clicking on here and
这看起来像是通过点击这里和
we see this is what's selected and our
我们看到这是被选中的 我们的
sky is now not being selected and so if
Sky现在未被选中 因此如果
we make changes here it's going to
我们在这里做改变 它将会
change the way that everything looks
改变一切事物的外观
except for the sky kind of remains white
除了天空仍然是白色的
and the same whereas if we weren't doing
同样的 如果我们不这样做
parametric masking the white the sky
参数遮罩天空中的白色
would have like a pink hue to it this
我想要粉色的这个
probably isn't the best the most
可能不是最好的
dramatic one to module two see the
戏剧性的一到模块二看到
differences here but we can make subtle
这里有不同之处 但我们可以微妙地
differences and again every module has
不同之处 每个模块都有
just about every module we can do our
几乎我们能做的每一个模块
contrast we could mask out we could use
相比之下 我们可以遮盖住我们可以使用的
parametric masking on our tone curve we
色调曲线上的参数掩码
could do parametric masking on so all
可以对所有对象进行参数遮罩
kinds of use cases for this and in the
这个应用程序和
next video we're gonna kind of solidify
下一个视频我们要巩固一下
this more by doing drawn and parametric
这更多是通过执行绘制和参数化
masking so there's a way we can
所以我们有一种方法可以
sometimes you will have a you'll want to
有时你会有一种你想要的
maybe just like this leaf here will want
也许就像这里的这片叶子一样
to select the the area of this
要选择此区域的
and then also do parametric masking
然后还可以进行参数掩码
either within it or outside of it and so
无论是在它的内部还是外部 所以
we can do drawn and parametric masking
我们可以进行绘制和参数遮罩
together using its own mode for that
一起使用它自己的模式
well I think I'm gonna leave this video
好吧 我想我要把这段视频
here go ahead and play with that I know
来吧 继续玩吧 我知道
we didn't cover everything in parametric
我们没有在参数中涵盖所有内容
masking next time we'll do maybe we'll
下一次我们会做面具 也许我们会
work with hue which gives us we can
用色调工作 这给了我们
select by a certain hue and we can do
按一定的色调选择 我们就可以
both at once
两者同时出现
absolute if we double click it resets it
绝对 如果我们双击它 它将重置
we can do both of these at once so we
我们可以同时做这两件事 所以我们
can select based on the luma channel and
可以根据亮度通道和
the hue at once and that kind of gives
色调一下子就给人一种
us more control over our mask but it
美国对我们的面具有更多的控制权 但它
gets a little bit more tricky and it's
变得更棘手了 这是
kind of harder just let pixels that way
有点难 只是让像素那样
as well play with parametric masking
以及玩参数掩蔽
it's gonna be a little bit confusing at
会有点混乱
first but at the more you play with it
首先 但你玩得越多
the more you'll realize situations when
你就越能意识到
it's good to use the parametric masks in
最好在
other situations where it's just going
其他情况下
to be better off using the drawn mask
为了更好地使用绘制的面具
and sometimes altogether you don't need
有时候你不需要
to use masking you can use certain nodes
要使用掩码 可以使用某些节点
like in this case we could have used the
就像在这种情况下我们可以用
color lookup table would have been a
颜色查找表将是一个
good one for adjusting certain covers of
一个很好的调整某些封面
this without doing masking at all anyway
无论如何
thanks for watching leave your questions
感谢收看留下您的问题
or comments below if you have any and
或评论下面 如果你有任何
we'll catch you in the next video
我们会在下一个视频中看到你